A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files,
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.061
The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access is prohibited for ten years from the date of creation unless special permission is granted by the President's Office. Under the terms of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act Sec. 2.1-343 (4), the records of the president or other chief executive officer of any state-supported institution of higher education are exempt from the law's access provisions.
Additional access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
These records were transferred from the Office of the President, Madison Hall, University of Virginia, through Peggy S. Pasternak, on September 29, 2006.
Scope and Content
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia, John Thomas Casteen, 11,000 items (36 Hollinger boxes, ca. 15 linear shelf feet) chiefly 2002-2004, but with some files, such as the Alumni Association Survey of Members and Prospective Members, going back to 1998, or Bryn Mawr College (1995).
The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office. Major topics include American Council on Education; Association of American Universities; athletics and the NCAA; the Council for Higher Education Accreditation; development; the General Assembly; gifts and grants; the Governor of Virginia's office; the Mariners' Museum; the Medical Center and the Health Services Foundation; Reserve Officers' Training Corps; State Council of Higher Education for Virginia; and Student Affairs.
Arrangement
Both the series and file headings used by the president's office have been retained. Restricted material has been placed in its own series. There are two series: Series I) General Files (Boxes 1-31); Series II) Restricted Files (Boxes 32-36).
Contents List
- Series I: General Files
  - "Aa-Ai" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - "Al" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - "Am" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - "An" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - "As-Ay" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Access UVA, 2004 February-March (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Admissions-General, 2004 May-June (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Admissions-General, 2004 March-April (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Admissions-General, 2004 January-February (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Admissions-General, 2003 November-December (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Admissions-General, 2003 May-October (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Admissions-Darden, 2004 February-May (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Admissions-Law, 2003 October-2004 March (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Admissions-Medical, 2003 November (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Office of African-American Affairs, 2003 May-2004 March (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Alumni Association- General & Board of Managers, 2003 November-2004 June (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Alumni Association-General & Board of Managers, 2003 September-October (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Alumni Association-General & Board of Managers, 2003 July-August (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Alumni Association-General & Board of Managers, 1998 March (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Alumni Relations Task Force, 2003 July-2004 April (Box-folder 3:5)
  - American Council on Education-General, 2004 January-June (Box-folder 3:6)
  - American Council on Education-General, 2003 July-December (Box-folder 4:1)
  - American Council on Education- The Presidency, 2003 November (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Anthropology, 2003 September (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Architecture, 2003 May-2004 May (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Art-General, 2003 July (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Art- Art Museum, 2003 April-2004 February (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Art-Arts, Planning, & Development, 2003 September-December (Box-folder 4:7)
  - Arts & Sciences-General, 2003 August-2004 June (Box-folder 4:8)
  - Association of American Colleges & Universities, 2003 August-2004 February (Box-folder 4:9)
  - Association of American Colleges & Universities-January Meeting (1 of 2 folders), 2004 January 21-22 (Box-folder 4:10)
  - Association of American Colleges & Universities- January Meeting (2 of 2 folders), 2004 January 21-22 (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Association of American Universities, 2004 April-May (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Association of American Universities, 2004 February-March (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Association of American Universities, 2004 January (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Association of American Universities, 2003 September-December (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Association of American Universities, 2003 July-August (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Association of American Universities-Fall Meeting, 2003 October (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Association of American Universities-Fall Meeting, 2003 October (Box-folder 6:1)
  - Association of American Universities-Spring Meeting, 2004 April (Box-folder 6:2)
  - Association of American Universities-Spring Meeting, 2004 April (Box-folder 6:3)
  - Association of Governing Boards, 2003 July-2004 May (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Astronomy, 2003 July-2004 April (Box-folder 6:5)
  - Athletics-General, 2004 January-June (Box-folder 6:6)
  - Athletics-General, 2003 July-December (Box-folder 6:7)
  - Athletics-Atlantic Coast Conference, 2004 March-May (Box-folder 7:1)
  - Athletics-Atlantic Coast Conference, 2003 August-2004 February (Box-folder 7:2)
  - Athletics- Atlantic Coast Conference, 2003 July (Box-folder 7:3)
  - Athletics- National Collegiate Athletic Association, 2004 April-June (Box-folder 7:4)
  - Athletics- National Collegiate Athletic Association, 2004 March (Box-folder 7:5)
  - Athletics-National Collegiate Athletic Association, 2003 October-2004 February (Box-folder 7:6)
  - Athletics- National Collegiate Athletic Association, 2003 July-September (Box-folder 7:7)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts (State), 2003 November-2004 January (Box-folder 7:8)
  - Aurbach, Gerald & Hannah, 2002 May-September (Box-folder 8:1)
  - Aurbach, Gerald & Hannah, 2002 October-2004 April (Box-folder 8:2)
  - "Ba-Be" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 8:3)
  - "Bi-Bl" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 8:4)
  - "Bo-Bro" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 8:5)
  - "Bry-By" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 8:6)
  - Bryn Mawr College/HERS, 1995 March-2004 May (Box-folder 8:7)
  - Business & Finance, 2004 March-June (Box-folder 9:1)
  - Business & Finance, 2003 November-2004 January (Box-folder 9:2)
  - Business & Finance, 2003 July-October (Box-folder 9:3)
  - "Ca" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 9:4)
  - "Ce-Chi" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 9:5)
  - "Cho-Cl" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 9:6)
  - "Coa-Com" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 10:1)
  - "Con-Cow" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 10:2)
  - "Cr-Cu" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 10:3)
  - California Trip, 2003 November (Box-folder 10:4)
  - Carr's Hill, 2003 July-2004 April (Box-folder 10:5)
  - Casteen, John T. III, 2003 August-2004 March (Box-folder 10:6)
  - Cavalier Daily, 2004 March-April (Box-folder 10:7)
  - City of Charlottesville, 2003 August-2004 May (Box-folder 10:8)
  - City of Charlottesville- Planning & Coordination Council, 2003 August-2004 June (Box-folder 10:9)
  - Charter Universities, 2004 May (Box-folder 11:1)
  - Class of 2004 Dinner, Alumni Hall, 2004 February 3 (Box-folder 11:2)
  - College Board, 2003 July-2004 May (Box-folder 11:3)
  - Commerce School, 2003 August-2004 May (Box-folder 11:4)
  - Commonwealth Public Broadcasting, 2003 July-2004 April (Box-folder 11:5)
  - Community Relations, 2003 July- 2004 June (Box-folder 11:6)
  - Condolences "A-J", 2003-2004 (Box-folder 11:7)
  - Condolences "K-Z", 2003-2004 (Box-folder 11:8)
  - Congress-General, 2003 July-September (Box-folder 11:9)
  - Continuing & Professional Studies, 2003 August-2004 June (Box-folder 12:1)
  - Council for Higher Education Accreditation, 2004 January- May (Box-folder 12:2)
  - Council for Higher Education Accreditation, 2003 July-December (Box-folder 12:3)
  - Council of Presidents, 2003 December-2004 June (Box-folder 12:4)
  - Council of Presidents, 2003 July-November (Box-folder 12:5)
  - "Da-Di" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 12:6)
  - "Do-Dy" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 12:7)
  - Darden School, 2004 April-June (Box-folder 13:1)
  - Darden School, 2003 July-2004 March (Box-folder 13:2)
  - Deans' Retreat, 2003 August (Box-folder 13:3)
  - Department of Emergency Management (Virginia), 2003 August-2004 May (Box-folder 13:4)
  - Development, 2003 July-2004 April (Box-folder 13:5)
  - Domestic Partner Benefits, 2004 February-March (Box-folder 13:6)
  - "Ea-El" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 13:7)
  - "Em-Ez" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 13:8)
  - Education School, 2003 July-2004 April (Box-folder 14:1)
  - Engineering & Applied Sciences, 2003 August-2004 May (Box-folder 14:2)
  - English, 2003 August (Box-folder 14:3)
  - Environmental Sciences, 2003 December-2004 April (Box-folder 14:4)
  - Equal Opportunity Office, 2003 July-2004 June (Box-folder 14:5)
  - "Fa-Fl" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 14:6)
  - "Fo-Fu" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 14:7)
  - Facilities Management, 2003 July-2004 April (Box-folder 14:8)
  - Faculty, 2003 October-2004 May (Box-folder 14:9)
  - Fall Convocation, 2003 September-2004 November (Box-folder 14:10)
  - Final Exercises, 2003 October-2004 May (Box-folder 14:11)
  - Finance, 2003 Juy-2004 May (Box-folder 15:1)
  - Financial Aid to Students, 2003 November-2004 March (Box-folder 15:2)
  - "Ga-Go" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 15:3)
  - "Gr-Gu" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 15:4)
  - Gallagher, Gary, 2003 July-August (Box-folder 15:5)
  - General Assembly, 2004 March-May (Box-folder 15:6)
  - General Assembly, 2004 February (Box-folder 15:7)
  - General Assembly, 2004 January (Box-folder 16:1)
  - General Assembly, 2003 December (Box-folder 16:2)
  - Governmental Relations, 2003 July-2004 April (Box-folder 16:3)
  - Governor's Office-General, 2003 June-2004 June (Box-folder 16:4)
  - Governor's Office-Education, 2003 July-2004 April (Box-folder 16:5)
  - Governor's Office-Public Safety & Transportation, 2004 April (Box-folder 16:6)
  - Governor's Office-Technology, 2004 February (Box-folder 16:7)
  - "Ha-Hi" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 16:8)
  - "Ho-Hu" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 17:1)
  - History, 2004 April (Box-folder 17:2)
  - Honor System & Committee, 2003 August-2004 June (Box-folder 17:3)
  - Housing, 2003 October-2004 May (Box-folder 17:4)
  - Human Resources, 2004 February-June (Box-folder 17:5)
  - Human Resources, 2003 July-2004 January (Box-folder 17:6)
  - "Ia-In" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 17:7)
  - "Ir-Is" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 17:8)
  - Information Technology (State), 2004 February (Box-folder 17:9)
  - Information Technology (UVA), 2003 September-2004 February (Box-folder 17:10)
  - Institutional Assessment & Studies, 2003 June-November (Box-folder 17:11)
  - International Studies, 2003 September-2004 February (Box-folder 18:1)
  - Irish Universities Quality Board, 2003 June-2004 June (Box-folder 18:2)
  - Invitations to Inaugurations "A-L", 2003-2004 (Box-folder 18:3)
  - Invitations to Inaugurations "M-T", 2003-2004 (Box-folder 18:4)
  - "J-Je" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 18:5)
  - "Jo-Ju" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 18:6)
  - Jefferson Memorial Foundation, Thomas, 2003 September-2004 April (Box-folder 19:1)
  - Jefferson Scholars Program, 2003 November-2004 June (Box-folder 19:2)
  - Johnson Foundation, Robert Wood, 2003 November (Box-folder 19:3)
  - Joint Legislative Audit & Review Commission, 2003 July-2004 May (Box-folder 19:4)
  - "Ka-Ke" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 19:5)
  - "Ki-Kr" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 19:6)
  - Keswick Club & Hall, 2003 July-2004 May (Box-folder 19:7)
  - "La" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 19:8)
  - "Le" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 19:9)
  - "Li-Lu" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 19:10)
  - Lark, Raymond, 2004 June (Box-folder 20:1)
  - Law School, 2003 October-2004 April (Box-folder 20:2)
  - Leiden, Netherlands Trip, 2004 May (Box-folder 20:3)
  - Library, 2003 August-2004 June (Box-folder 20:4)
  - "Ma" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 20:5)
  - "Mc-Me" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 20:6)
  - "Mi-Mu" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 21:1)
  - Mariners' Museum, 2004 May-June (Box-folder 21:2)
  - Mariners' Museum, 2004 January-April (Box-folder 21:3)
  - Mariners' Museum, 2003 November-December (Box-folder 21:4)
  - Mariners' Museum, 2003 July-October (Box-folder 21:5)
  - Mathematics, 2003 July-2004 April (Box-folder 21:6)
  - Medical Center-General, 2003 July-2004 May (Box-folder 21:7)
  - Medical Center-Hospital, 2004 May (Box-folder 21:8)
  - Medical Center-Medical School, 2004 March-May (Box-folder 22:1)
  - Medical Center-Medical School, 2004 February (Box-folder 22:2)
  - Medical Center-Medical School, 2003 August (Box-folder 22:3)
  - Medical Center-Nursing School, 2003 August-2004 April (Box-folder 22:4)
  - Medical Center-Personnel, 2003 September (Box-folder 22:5)
  - Mellon Foundation, Andrew W., 2003 July-2004 April (Box-folder 22:6)
  - Music, 2003 September-2004 April (Box-folder 22:7)
  - "N-Nat" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 22:8)
  - "Nau-Ne" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 23:1)
  - "No-Np" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 23:2)
  - National Association of State Universities & Land-Grant Colleges, 2003 September-2004 June (Box-folder 23:3)
  - "O" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 23:4)
  - Otley Hall, 2003 April-August (Box-folder 23:5)
  - "Pa" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 23:6)
  - "Pe" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 24:1)
  - "Ph-Pl" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 24:2)
  - "Po-Pu" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 24:3)
  - Polish Chair, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 24:4)
  - Politics, 2003 August-2004 April (Box-folder 24:5)
  - President's Senior Cabinet, 2003 August-2004 May (Box-folder 24:6)
  - Provost, 2004 May-June (Box-folder 24:7)
  - Provost, 2004 April (Box-folder 24:8)
  - Provost, 2004 February-March (Box-folder 25:1)
  - Provost, 2003 September-2004 January (Box-folder 25:2)
  - Provost, 2003 July-August (Box-folder 25:3)
  - "Q-Ren" Miscellaneous, including information about the Woods family and the dedication of Ren Ci Yi Yuan Hospital in China, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 25:4)
  - "Rep-Ri" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 25:5)
  - "Ro-Ru" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 25:6)
  - Recommendations "B-S", 2003-2004 (Box-folder 25:7)
  - Registrar, 2003 December (Box-folder 25:8)
  - Religious Studies, 2003 August (Box-folder 25:9)
  - Research & Graduate Studies, 2003 September-2004 May (Box-folder 25:10)
  - Requests for Nominations, 2003 July-2004 June (Box-folder 25:11)
  - Reserve Officers' Training Corps, 2003 July-2004 June (Box-folder 26:1)
  - "Sa-Sh" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 26:2)
  - "Si-Sos" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 26:3)
  - "Sou-Sp" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 26:4)
  - "St-Sy" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 26:5)
  - Senate, Faculty, 2003 September-2004 April (Box-folder 26:6)
  - Slavic Languages & Literatures, 2004 April (Box-folder 26:7)
  - Small, Albert, 2003 July-2004 May (Box-folder 26:8)
  - Southern Association of Colleges & Schools, 2003 July-2004 May (Box-folder 27:1)
  - State Council of Higher Education for Virginia, 2003 November-2004 May (Box-folder 27:2)
  - State Council of Higher Education for Virginia, 2003 July-October (Box-folder 27:3)
  - State Department of Education, 2003 August (Box-folder 27:4)
  - Student Affairs-General, 2004 January-September (Box-folder 27:5)
  - Student Affairs-General, 2003 December (Box-folder 27:6)
  - Student Affairs-General, 2003 November-December (Box-folder 27:7)
  - Student Affairs-General, 2003 July-October (Box-folder 27:8)
  - Student Affairs-Dean of Students, 2004 February-March (Box-folder 28:1)
  - Student Affairs-Fraternities & Sororities, 2003 October-2004 February (Box-folder 28:2)
  - Student Council, 2003 July-September (Box-folder 28:3)
  - Summer Session, 2003 December-2004 March (Box-folder 28:4)
  - "Ta-Th" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 28:5)
  - "Ti-Ty" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 28:6)
  - "U-Unit" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 28:7)
  - "Univ-Us" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 28:8)
  - United States Department of Education, 2003 July-2004 February (Box-folder 28:9)
  - United Way/Combined Charitable Campaign, 2003 August-2004 April (Box-folder 28:10)
  - University of Virginia-College at Wise, 2004 March-June (Box-folder 28:11)
  - University of Virginia Investment Management Company, 2004 April-May (Box-folder 28:12)
  - University of Virginia Investment Management Company, 2003 October- 2004 March (Box-folder 29:1)
  - University of Virginia Investment Management Company, 2003 July-September (Box-folder 29:2)
  - University of Virginia Press, 2003 July-2004 June (Box-folder 29:3)
  - University Police, 2003 September-2004 June (Box-folder 29:4)
  - University Relations/News Office, 2003 July-2004 April (Box-folder 29:5)
  - "Va-Via" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 29:6)
  - "Vir-Virginia E" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 29:7)
  - "Virginia F-Virginia T" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 30:1)
  - "Vo" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 30:2)
  - Vice Presidents' Retreat, 2003 August (Box-folder 30:3)
  - Virginia 2020, 2003 July-November (Box-folder 30:4)
  - Virginia Business Higher Education Council, 2003 August-2004 March (Box-folder 30:5)
  - Virginia Festival of American Film, 2003 August-2004 March (Box-folder 30:6)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review, 2003 November (Box-folder 30:7)
  - "Wa-Wc" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 30:8)
  - "We-Wh" Micellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 31:1)
  - "Wi" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 31:2)
  - "Wo-Wy" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 31:3)
  - Women's Center, 2003 August2004 April (Box-folder 31:4)
  - Weldon Cooper Center for Public Service, 2003 December (Box-folder 31:5)
  - "Y-Z" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 31:6)
- Series II: Restricted Files
  - "A" Restricted, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 32:1)
  - Admissions-General, Restricted, 2003 August-2004 May (Box-folder 32:2)
  - Applications for Positions, 2003 July-2004 June (Box-folder 32:3)
  - "B" Restricted, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 32:4)
  - Budget Defense Fund, 2004 March-April (Box-folder 32:5)
  - Business & Finance, 2004 April-June (Box-folder 32:6)
  - Business & Finance, 2003 July-2004 March (Box-folder 32:7)
  - "C" Restricted, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 32:8)
  - California Trip, 2004 May (Box-folder 32:9)
  - California Trip, 2003 November, 2004 January (Box-folder 33:1)
  - Condolences "A-Z", 2003-2004 (Box-folder 33:2)
  - "D-E" Restricted, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 33:3)
  - Engineering & Applied Sciences, 2003 July-2004 June (Box-folder 33:4)
  - "F" Restricted, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 33:5)
  - "G" Restricted, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 33:6)
  - Gifts & Grants "A-Br", 2003-2004 (Box-folder 33:7)
  - Gifts & Grants "Bu-De", 2003-2004 (Box-folder 34:1)
  - Gifts & Grants "Di-Go", 2003-2004 (Box-folder 34:2)
  - Gifts & Grants "Gr-Ka", 2003-2004 (Box-folder 34:3)
  - Gifts & Grants "Ke-Mc", 2003-2004 (Box-folder 34:4)
  - Gifts & Grants "Md-Pe", 2003-2004 (Box-folder 34:5)
  - Gifts & Grants "Pf-St", 2003-2004 (Box-folder 34:6)
  - Gifts & Grants "Su-Wh", 2003-2004 (Box-folder 35:1)
  - Gifts & Grants "Wi-Y", 2003-2004 (Box-folder 35:2)
  - "H-I" Restricted, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 35:3)
  - "L-M" Restricted, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 35:4)
  - Management & Budget, 2003 December-2003 June (Box-folder 35:5)
  - Management & Budget, 2003 July-August (Box-folder 35:6)
  - "N" Restricted, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 35:7)
  - "P" Restricted, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 36:1)
  - "R-S" Restricted, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 36:2)
  - "T-U" Restricted, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 36:3)
  - Texas Trip, 2004 March-April (Box-folder 36:4)
  - "W" Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 36:5)